Mohammaduwais Mulla

To obtain a challenging position in Cyber security where I can utilize my skills and experience to contribute to the company's success. I am Highly motivated and detailed-oriented Cyber Security Analyst with 2+ years of experience in threat detection, incident response, and security monitoring. Proficient in Azure sentinel, SIEM, and log analysis.

Ansar Galli, Peerenwadi, Belgaum, Karnataka 590014 (+91) 9480416253 uwais.co.in123@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Wipro, Hyderabad — Security Analyst

September 2023 - PRESENT

- Monitor and analyze security alerts from multiple log sources, including azure sentinel to identify potential threats and incidents.
- Investigate and mitigate security Incidents, including root cause and remediation recommendation.
- As per client requirement preparing various reports related to security incidents (Weekly and monthly reports).
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams, including incident response, threat intelligence, and security engineering, to ensure effective incident response and remediation.
- Develop and maintain documentation of security incidents, including incident reports and post-mortem analysis.

Concentrix, Pune— *SOC Analyst*

April 2022 - May 20203

- Provide 24/7 security monitoring and incident response for a large-scale cloud-based infrastructure.
- Assist during shift changes for ongoing tasks.
- Analyzed logs from Azure sentinel to identify security threats and incidents.
- Identified and prioritized security threats based on risk and impact, and escalated incidents to senior management as needed.
- Worked in agile environment, collaborating with development teams to integrate security into the software development lifecycle.
- Tracking alerts on daily bases and highlighted to higher management.

SKILLS

Security information.and Event Management (SIEM).

Azure Sentinel.

Endpoint detection and response (EDR)

Computer Networking

Log analysis

Troubleshooting

Incident Response

Operation Systems (Windows, MacOS)

LANGUAGES

English (Proficient)

Hindi (Proficient)

Kannada (Proficient)

Marathi (Proficient)

EDUCATION

Jain College of Engineering, Belagavi

August 2017 - July 2020

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical.

Jain polytechnic Belagavi,

June 2014 - July 2017
Diploma in mechanical.

PROJECTS

Tensile stress analysis of a mild steel specimen.